Stern, Sarah Cammerstein Triangle Fire Collection 6373
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Sarah Cammerstein Stern Triangle Fire Collection
1911-1999
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Stern, Sarah Cammerstein
6373
0.83 cubic feet
0.8 linear ft.
News clippings.
8399844
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, February 20, 2014
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, October 23, 2015
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Triangle Shirtwaist Company -- Fire, 1911
8399844
- Letters from Maurice Stern to Sarah Cammerstein, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Affidavit for License to Marry for Maurice Stern and Sarah Cammerstein, 1911-1912 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Scope and Contents
  Date of Marriage entered as December 31, 1911. Affidavit sworn on December 29, 1912.
- Roll of Dead in Waist Factory Fire Numbers 141; Sixty Bodies of Victims Are Still Unidentified, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  The New York Herald, March 27, 1911. Photocopy
- Twenty-Five Years Ago This Week: Triangle Waist Fire Cost 146 Lives and Caused Wide Reforms, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Sunday News, March 22, 1936
- Neptune Service News, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  February 1944.
- New Safety Era Born of Fire Horror: Code of Laws a Memorial to 145 Girls Who Died In Triangle Factory Trap, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  New York World-Telegram, November 29, 1950.
- Ten Minutes of Terror: Today's Stringent Work Laws Forged in Sweatshop Holocaust That Claimed 146 Lives Half Century Ago, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Sunday News, March 19, 1961.
- Memories of a Fire A Half-Century Ago, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  New York Post, March 26, 1961.
- March 25, 1911: The Day It Rained Burning Girls, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Cavalier Magazine, June 1961.
- TV Drama Brings Back Memories of Fire, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Fort Lauderdale News, January 30, 1979.
- The Shirtwaist Fire, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Printed from www.historybuff.com/library/refshirtwaist.html on February 26, 1999. First section missing. Printed again in its entirety on February 20, 2014.
- Letter, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  6 pages